CURRICULUM VITAE

Bonface Mburugu Kaburu

P.O Box 1182-60200,

Meru

Phone No.: 0726502870/0735909392

Email address: mburugu.bonface@gmail.com

SUMMARY

A registered pharmacist with over eight years' experience in pharmacy practice and holder of a Bachelor of Pharmacy degree (MKU) and a Diploma in Pharmaceutical Technology (KNEC).

The more than three years spent as the research and compliance officer at Modern Ways Ltd/ Vital Animal Health, an importer and distributor of veterinary pharmaceuticals and manufacturer of animal mineral supplements, gave me adequate experience in product registration and product retention with the various regulatory authorities including the Pharmacy and poisons Board (PPB), Pest Control Products Board (PCPB), Kenya Bureau of Standards KEBS), Directorate of Veterinary Medicines (DVS), KEPHIS among others. It gave me an insight on working in complex organizations and improved my interpersonal skills through interaction with people from different professional backgrounds. It also helped me refine my managerial skills and grew my network and contacts in different sectors and government regulatory bodies. I was a member of a KEBS technical committee for three years.

My passion is in regulatory affairs as it is the backbone of the pharmaceutical industry and have a keen interest in the Kenyan health laws. My passion is to pursue a career in the pharmaceutical industry and in particular in regulatory affairs and thus make use of the knowledge and competences so far gained and even as I gain more experience.

EDUCATION BACKGROUND

May 2010 – December 2015: Mount Kenya University

Bachelor of Pharmacy

January 2006 - November 2009: Thika Institute of Technology

Diploma in Pharmaceutical Technology

Grade: Pass.

February 2001 - November 2004: Nkubu Boys High School (Meru)

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education

Grade: B.

January 1997 - November 2000: Abothuguchi Boarding Primary School (Meru)

Kenya Certificate of Primary Education

Total marks: 524/700.

TRAININGS

August 2019 – Directorate of Occupational Safety & Health Services (DOSHS)

Occupational Health and Safety

31st August- 2nd September 2015: Division of malaria Control (MOH)

Training on national guidelines for the diagnosis, treatment and prevention of malaria in Kenya

Alpha Safety Services Ltd:

Occupational first aid course

September 2014- Royal Society for Public Heath (USA) and Land O'lakes

• Hazard analysis and critical control point Level 3 certification (Distinction)

Professional qualification and association registrations

2019: Registered pharmacist - Pharmacy and Poisons Board (PPB)

Registration No.: 3549

2019: Registered member – Pharmaceutical Society of Kenya (**PSK**)

Membership No.: 3549

2011-2018: Enrolled pharmaceutical technologist - Pharmacy and Poisons Board (PPB)

Enrolment No.: 4117

2011- Registered member – Kenya Pharmaceutical Association (KPA)

Membership No.: 3357

WORK EXPERIENCE

July 2019- to date: Company Pharmacist & Head, Regulatory Affairs

Surgilinks Ltd

Duties:

• Preparing regulatory dossiers for new products and ensuring that the licences are maintained.

• To monitor and report all adverse events and customer complaints reported.

Manage the relationship with regulatory authorities in Kenya on matters relating to regulatory

approvals for Surgilinks Ltd products, respond to queries and requests for additional information.

Continuously track and ensure product licenses are maintained through timely renewal, re-

registration and submission of variations, amendments and notifications.

Maintain a document filing system to ensure easy access of documentation and product history

throughout the product life cycle and maintain regulatory status reports of all regulatory active

products.

Monitor and report all adverse events and customer complaints reported for all consumer

products.

Manage Quality Management System Audits and tracks the implementation of audit findings.

• Informing the respective manufacturers represented on the status of their products in Kenya.

• Linkage between the foreign drug manufacturers and the PPB/Analysis Laboratories

Linkage between the surgilinks and PPB

Following up on IDF's and permits at the PPB

Handling all product recalls

• Checking whether our prospective customers are registered to deal with medicines before

accounts are opened.

Making relevant applications on behalf of Surgilinks and all the manufacturers it represents.

Preparing samples and documentation for analysis

• Handling of expiries, damaged nd obsolete drugs by ensuring that drugs are quarantined.

Providing drug information required to the medical reps, surgilinks staff and answering to

customer queries.

September 2018 – June 2019: Pharmacist

Kimathi Street Medical Centre (Nairobi)

September 2017- September 2018: Pharmacist internship training

Ministry of Health/Pharmacy and Poisons Board

- Kaiti Pharmacy (Wote)
- Makueni County Referral Hospital
- Biopharma Ltd

August 2014 – August 2017: Research and Compliance officer

Modern Ways Ltd (Vital Animal Health).

Duties:

- Preparing and submitting product dossiers for registration and retention of pharmaceuticals, pesticides, borderline products and animal supplements by the relevant regulatory authorities.
- Handling the company's regulatory requirements including premise, personnel, export and import licenses on time.
- Ensuring timely renewal of the annual KEBS Standard mark permits for the animal mineral supplements (Vital range)
- Preparing of Standard Operating Procedures and implementing best practices in regards to current regulations and standards of ethical and professional performance.
- Linkage to Pharmacy and Poisons Board, Pest Control Products Board, KEBS, Department of Veterinary Services and other regulatory agencies.
- Coordinating training programs for staff members on GDP, pharmaco-vigilance, first aid, fire safety, occupational safety and health, occupational hazard etc.
- Auditing the internal systems and following up on the implementation of proposed corrective actions.
- Monitoring and evaluating products for compliance with the set national standards and other approved own standards by submitting samples for testing to accredited laboratories for analysis
- Management of the stores as per Good Storage Practice and Good Distribution Practices
- Temperature mapping of storage areas.
- Preparation of tender documents for submission to respective organizations.

May 2014 – June 2014: Pharmaceutical technologist

Nazareth Hospital, Limuru

Duties:

- Patient counselling and education
- Promoting rational drug use

- Dispensing according to internally generated prescriptions;
- Dispensing of drugs for the inpatients
- Maintains records by recording all dispensed prescriptions
- Reporting on stock status
- Preparing reports by collecting and summarizing drug use information.

April 2012 – April 2014: Pharmaceutical technologist-in-charge

Gaichanjiru Catholic Hospital - Murang'a

Duties:

- Receiving prescriptions and dispensing drugs accordingly
- Patient counselling and follow-up
- Day to day running of the pharmacy department.
- Promoting rational drug use
- Managing pharmaceutical and non-pharmaceutical products stocks
- Ordering of pharmaceutical and non-pharmaceutical products from MEDS, KEMSA and independent suppliers
- Preparing of monthly consumption reports for malaria drugs, ARVs and TB drugs
- Preparing and reviewing pharmacy department's SOP
- Ensuring that SOPs are implemented to increase efficiency in pharmaceutical services and minimize errors
- Participating in drug safety management (Pharmaco-vigilance)
- Preparing the budget for the pharmacy department
- Provision of drug information to other health workers
- Attending meeting, forums and workshops organized by Ministry of Health, PPB and other relevant organizations
- Member of the healthcare team and participating in ward rounds
- Preparing duty rota for the pharmacy department

August 2011 - March 2012: Pharmaceutical technologist

Florentine Chemist Thika

Duties:

- Dispensing drugs and medications
- Patient counselling
- Diagnosing and treating minor illnesses
- Maintaining general cleanliness in the pharmacy
- Pricing drugs and non-pharms stocked
- Ordering drugs and maintaining adequate stocks

COMMUNITY OUTREACH

2016-to date: member, Building & Development Committee, Methodist Church of Kenya (Thika Church).

2017-to date: Secretary, Men Fellowship, Methodist Church of Kenya (Thika Church)

2015-to date: Mentor Kijijone Primary School in Meru Central District.

2010 -to date: Board member Hands of Hope & Peace Volunteers

HOBBIES

• Reading novels, newspapers, magazines and journals

- Travelling, hiking and sight seeing
- Watching movies and documentaries
- Participating in community outreaches
- Planning, organizing and coordinating events

REFEREES

Dr. Stephen Kimathi,
 The Director,
 Medicines Information and Pharmacovigilance (MIPV)
 Pharmacy and Poisons Board
 0722346655

 Dr. Kerubo Bichanga, Clinical Pharmacist, Makueni County Referral Hospital, 0720527410.

Dr. Rebecca Mutisya,
 Pharmacist,
 Mwai Kibaki Referral Hospital (Othaya)
 0720876398.